Ngũgĩ mss., ca. 1950s-2014 LMC 2905
Lilly Library
- III. Writings by Others
  - Scholarly Papers
    - Goro, Wangui wa - Tradition and Translation in African Letters: The Issue of Language Translation: The Future (Box 30)
    - Graham, Yo - Ghana-The Politics of Crisis: Class Struggle and Organization, 1976-1983 (Box 30)
    - Granqvist, Raoul - Gary Gilmore's Pilgrimage: A Study of Norman Mailer's The Executioner's Song (Box 30)
    - Green, Ernest - A Critique of Neoclassical Theory (Box 30)
    - Green, R.J. - South Africa's Plague: On View of the Blood Knot (Box 31)
    - Gregerson, Maren - The 1994 South African Elections (Box 31)
    - Grundy, Kenneth W. - On Machiavelli and the Mercenaries (Box 31)
    - Hairu, Ichiro - Toward the Goal of Changing the World Through People's Culture (Box 31)
    - Hilal, Jamil - Imperialism and Settler-Colonialism in West Asia: Israel and the Arab Palestinian Struggle, 1976 (Box 31)
    - Hassan, Amani - Nawal Saadawi (Box 31)
    - Hawkins - Audrey N. - Writing Riots: The Politics and Culture in Kenyan Theater (Box 31)
    - Hegmar, Engil - Agriculture Development in Kenya with Special Reference to Eastern Division, Kitui District (Box 31)
    - Heron - G.A. - Anglophone Writers and Critics from East and West Africa: A Comparison (Box 31)
    - Hossain, Ruhela - Banning of Political Activities and the Roots of the Culture of Violence: The Roles of the SACP, ANC, and PAC Pre-1960 (Box 31)
    - Hull, Glen - African Student Attitudes: The Report of a Survey Conducted at Northwestern University (Box 31)
    - Hymer - Stephen - Robinson Crusoe and the Secret of Primitive Accumulation (Box 31)
    - Ikiddeh, Ime - 'Woman is Poison': The Character of Popular Fiction in Ghana (Box 31)
    - Indagasi, Henry - The Universal and the Particular in Literature (Box 31)
    - Irele, Abiola - Tradition and the Yoruba Writer D.O. Fagunwa, Amos Tutuola, and Wole Soyinka (Box 31)
    - Jones, N.M.K. - Report to the University of Leeds Subcommittee on Developing Countries (Box 31)
    - Kamenju, Grant - Black Aesthetics and Pan-African Emancipation (Box 31)
    - Karega, Mzalendo - Writings by Ndungi wa Mungai (Box 31)
    - Karia, K. - African Folklore Retentions in the Diaspora (Box 31)
    - Khubchandani, Prof. Lachman M. - Language Policy for a Pluralistic Society (Box 31)
    - Kibwana, Kivutha - Analytical Positivism in Kenya: A Preliminary Enquiry (Box 31)
    - Kiiru, Muchugu - Pessimism in East African Literature (Box 31)
    - Kimari, Githieya Muchigi - How Socialism has Prejudiced Africa's Evolving Political Thought (Box 31)
    - Kinyanjui, Kabiru (Box 31)
      - Education and Society in Kenya: Towards a Theoretical Framework for Analyzing Education (Box 31)
      - Regional Distribution of Education and Differentiation of Schools in Kenya (Box 31)
      - Some Aspects of Distribution of Education in Kenya (Box 31)
    - Kinyatti, Maina wa - Mau Mau: The Peak of African Political Organization in Colonial Kenya (Box 31)
    - Kubo, Satomi - Popular Cultural Movements: Experience and Prospects (Box 31)
    - Kuper, Leo - Political Change in Plural Societies: Problems in Racial Pluralism, 1971 (Box 31)
    - Kuria, Gibson Kamau - Religion, the Constitution and Family Law and Succession in Kenya (Box 31)
    - Lemarchand, René - Revolutionary Phenomena in Stratified Societies: Rwanda and Zanzibar (Box 31)
    - Leys, Colin (Box 31)
      - Security and Insecurity in Namibia: Policing in the Transition from Military Occupation to Independence (Box 31)
      - From the Margins at the Centre: Independence in/of Namibia (Box 31)
    - Littrup, Lisbeth - National Identity in Malay Literature: Fatimah Busu's Short Stories (Box 31)
    - Livingstone, Ian (Box 31)
      - The Rural and Urban Dimensions of the Informal Sector: A Discussion of Kenya (Box 31)
      - The 'Sponge Effect': Population, Employment and Incomes in Kenya (Box 31)
    - Liyong', Taban lo - What Shall We Demand From African Writers (Box 31)
    - Lonsdale, John M./Bruce J. Berman Louis Leakey's Mau Mau (Box 31)
    - Mahood, M.M. - The Embodiment of the Speaking Voice: Some French and English Contrasts (Box 31)
    - Majid, Farida - Tagore's Own Translations: Blindness and a Hindsight (Box 31)
    - Manji, Ambreena - Law, Literature and the Politics of Culture in Kenya (Box 31)
    - Masanja, P. - Neocolonialism and Revolution in Africa (Box 31)
    - Masilela, Ntongela - New African Modernity and New African Movement (Box 31)
    - Mazuri, Ali A. (Box 31)
      - The English Language and Political Consciousness in British Colonial Africa (Box 31)
      - The Legal Expression of Autocracy: The Example of Kenya (Box 31)
      - To the Africans and Back: The Aftermath of a Television Series (Box 31)
      - Political Theory and National Involvement in East Africa (Box 31)
    - Mbiti, John S. - Literature and the Oral Traditions (Box 31)
    - McKibben, Sarah Elizabeth - Lamenting Language: On the Metaphor of Dying Irish (Box 31)
    - Mirii, Ngũgĩ Wa (Box 31)
      - Church, Society and Development: A Challenge to Pastors (Box 31)
      - Community Arts and the Question of Culture in the City of Harare (Box 31)
      - Report of a Survey on Training Needs for Cultural Personnel in East, Central, and Southern Africa (Box 31)
      - On Literacy Content (Box 31)
    - Mojan, Jitendra - A Whig Interpretation of African Nationalism (Box 31)
    - Mohidin, Ahmed (Box 31)
      - At a Public Debate in Democracy, September 3, 1969 (Box 31)
      - Towards Relevant Culture and Politics in Africa (Box 31)
    - Moix, Bridget & William D. Hartung - Deadly Legacy: U.S. Arms to Africa and the Congo War (Box 31)
    - Montague, Dena - Economic Roots of U.S. Interests in the Congo (Box 31)
    - Mouhtadi, Abdelhak - A New Challenge to the African Writer in Search of Social Relevance (Box 31)
    - Mugo, Micere Githae - Language and Revolution with Reference to Afro-American Literature (Box 31)
    - Muiu, Mueni Wa - Fundi Wa Afrika: Toward a New Paradigm of the African State (Box 31)
    - Munene, Macharia - The Kikuyu Response to Kikuyu Bashing (Box 31)
    - Munoru, C.G.S. - Kenyan Jurisprudence and African Socialism (Box 31)
    - Murungi, Kiraitu - Political Oppression, Repression and Gross Violations of Human Rights in Kenya (Box 31)
    - Mutahi, Karega - Language and Politics in Kenya (Box 31)
    - Mutambanengwe, Lovemore - Racialism (Box 31)
    - Mutiso, G.C.M. - Cleavage and the Organizational Base of Politics in Kenya: A Theoretical Framework (Box 31)
    - Mutunga, Willy (Box 31)
      - Kenya: Contract Law and Society – A study of Rivatex's Investment and Management Agreements (Box 31)
      - Who Will Be the Cat? The Hire Purchase Act, 1968 and Possible Petty-Bourgeois Reforms (Box 32)
    - Nandwa, Jane Awinja - The Role of Children in Kenyan Oral Narratives (Box 32)
    - Neil, Michael - "Groping Behind a Mirror": Some Images of Other in South African Writing (Box 32)
    - Differentiation of the Peasantry and the Development of Capitalism in the Central Province of Kenya 1880-1970s (Box 32)
    - Ng'ang'a, D. Mukaru (Box 32)
      - Inequalities of Coffee Co-Operative Societies (The Case of Murang'a District) (Box 32)
      - Mau Mau and Kenyan Resistance (Box 32)
    - Njogu, Kimani & Ann Biersteker - Multilingualism in Kenya (Box 32)
    - Njorge, Peter Kiarie - The Role of Religion in Our Education System (Box 32)
    - Nyong'o, P. Anyang' - Class Struggles in Kenya (Box 32)
    - Ochieng', William R. (Box 32)
      - The Sheep and Goats Among the Kikuyu (Box 32)
      - The Interior of East Africa: The Peoples of Kenya and Tanzania: 1500-1800 (Box 32)
    - Odhiambo, Atieno - Democracy and the Ideology of Order in Kenya (Box 32)
    - Ogundele, Wole (Box 32)
      - For Unity and Progress', or Western Education and Alienation in Contemporary African Cultural Affairs (Box 32)
      - Playing at Modernity: or the Language Game in Postcolonial Africa, 1996 (Box 32)
    - Oruka, Odera H. - A Theory of Justice and Authoritative Myth for the Defense of Injustice (Box 32)
    - Okpaku, Sr., Dr. Joseph - Africa in the Year 2025: Peace, Governance and Culture (Box 32)
    - Osoti, W. - The Language of a Writer: Analysis of Ayi Kwei Armah's Novels (Box 32)
    - PADRIGU - Mozambique – The Troubled Transition (Box 32)
    - p'Bitek, Okot - The Crisis in the Teaching of Literature in East African Universities (Box 32)
    - Papa, Nene - A Brief Background of the Kikuyu People (Box 32)
    - Praft, Leighton - Language, Literature and Cultural Identity: The Irish Experience and it's Relevance to Africa (Box 32)
    - Pugliese, Cristina - The Life-Story in Kenya: A Bibliography (1920-1984) (Box 32)
    - Ravell-Pinto, Thelma M. - Women's Writing and the Politics of South Africa: The Ambiguous Role of Nadine Gordimer (Box 32)
    - Reddock, Rhonda - Towards an Integrated Analysis of Race, Class and Gender in the Caribbean (Box 32)
    - Reiss, Timothy J. (Box 32)
      - Denying the Body, Creating the Self? Histories and Identities (Box 32)
      - Descartes, Slavery and Race (Box 32)
      - History and Language Against Cultural Essences: Between Africa and the U.S. (Box 32)
    - Riccio, Thomas - Acting French: Theatre and Hegemony in Post-Colonial Francophone West Africa (Box 32)
    - Said, Edward W. - Cultural Hegemony or Cultural Exchanges? From Moody to Counterpoint (Box 32)
    - Schipper. Mineke (editor) - Black Paradise: African Creation and Origin Myths (Box 32)
    - Sebeok, Thomas A. - Folksong Viewed as Code and Message A Cheremis Sonnet (Box 32)
    - Sekitoleko, Victoria - The African Women on the Continent, State, Prospects and Strategy (Box 32)
    - Seymour, Hillary - Textual Silences: An Exploration of Patriarchy in Things Fall Apart and God's Bits of Wood (Box 32)
    - Skutnabb-Kangas, Tove - Linguistic Diversity, Human Rights and the 'Free' Market (Box 32)
    - Shivji, Issa G. - Tanzania: The Class Struggle Continues (Box 32)
    - Input Papers from SIDA 25th Anniversary Workshop "Development Assistance in the 1990s: Adjusting the Perspective" (Box 32)
    - Spaulding, Jay - An Historical Context for the Study of Islam in Eastern Africa (Box 32)
    - Somjee, Sultan (Box 32)
      - Culture of Democracy as a Contesting Culture (Box 32)
      - On Art and Society (Box 32)
      - On Material Cultures of the Nationalities and the Development of National Art (Box 32)
    - Ssekamwa, J.C. - Kiswahii Revolution Through Uganda's Education System (Box 32)
    - Thomas, Jennifer R. - Reasoned Madness: Women Articulating the Colonial Experience (Box 32)
    - Thompson, George - Marxism and Poetry (Box 32)
    - Tjwan, Go Gien - The Changing Trade Position of the Chinese in South-East Asia (Box 32)
    - Tsuchiya, Satoru - The Prospects for the African Culture: A Case of the Comparative Study Between African and Japanese Culture (Box 32)
    - Ulyanovsky, Prof. Rostislav - Scientific Socialism and Franz Fanon (Box 32)
    - Usman, Yusuf Bala - Karl Marx and the Analyses of the Politics of Contemporary Africa (Box 32)
    - Wang'Ombe, Mariga T. - African Education and National Development in Kenya During the 20th Century: A Survey (Box 32)
    - Wanjala, Chris L. - Words? Ah Yes, Words! A Discussion of Cesaire's Responsibilities as a Poet (Box 32)
    - Wolf, Jr., W. C./Douglas Passanisi - The Social and Political Consequences of Language Planning in Mozambique (Box 32)
    - Worthen, W.B. - Disciplines of the Text/Sites of Performance (Box 32)
    - Zishiri, Comrade P. Canisius - Education for a Revolutionary Change in Zimbabwe (Box 32)
    - Unknown (Box 32)
      - Cuba: The Untold Story (Box 32)
      - Female Characterization in the Literary Works of Ousmane Sembène (Box 32)
      - My Brother, My Guest, or Afro-Americans in Africa (Box 32)
      - Parsi Theatres: Early Indian Modernism (incomplete) (Box 32)
      - The Quest for Cultural Identity and the Individuation of Cultures (Box 32)
      - A Round Unvarnished Tale: (Mis) reading Othello of African-American strategies of Dissent [Jackie?] (Box 32)
      - Women's group study (incomplete) (Box 32)
  - Speeches/Lectures
    - Achebe, Chinua - Work and Play in Tutuola's Palm-Wine Drinkard First Equinao Memorial Lecture University of Ibadan (Box 32)
    - Kariuki, JM(?) (Box 32)
    - Kenyatta, Jomo - Harambee! The Prime Minister of Kenya's Speeches, 1963-1964 (Box 32)
    - Mutumbuka, Dzingai - The Aims and Nature of Education in Zimbabwe (Box 32)
    - Ng'weno, Hilary - Freedom of Expression, March 2,1981 (Box 32)
    - Njorge, Prof. Raphael J. - Philosophy and Education for Liberation and Creativity – Kenyatta University Inaugural Lecture-4, November 29, 1990 (Box 32)
    - Nyere, Julius K. (Box 32)
      - Speech to teachers at Dar es Salam, January 31, 1969 (Box 32)
      - Education for Self-Reliance, March, 1967 (Box 33)
    - Odinga, Jaramogi Oginga - Africa: A Continent in Crisis, Nairobi, July 28, 1981 (Box 33)
    - Seeiso, Crown Prince Mohato - Statement at the Symposium on Child Survival and Development, Harare, March 2, 1988 (Box 33)
    - Shongwe, A.V. - No More Lies About Africa, University of Zululand, June 21, 1994 (Box 33)
    - Unknown - Comrades, Sisters and Brothers, April 21,1987 (Box 33)
  - Gĩkũyũ (Kikuyu)
    - Correspondence (Box 33)
    - Kikuyu Orthography (Karega Mutahi) (Box 33)
    - The Phonetic and Tonal Structure of Kikuyu - Lilas E. Armstrong, 1940 (Box 33)
    - Mwandĩkĩre wa Gĩĩgĩkũyũ Karĩng'a (Writing of Proper Gikuyu) - Gakaara wa Wanjaũ (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Workshop in Gikuyu Orthography - Cege wa Githiora, Boston University (Box 33)
    - The Problem of Class in Kikuyu - Patrick R. Bennett (Box 33)
    - Mahooya Ma Kĩrĩndĩ [Ngũgĩ wa Mĩriĩ] (play?) (Box 33)
    - Karĩũkĩ wa Ndũũcũ (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - The Last Queen by Justus W. Nderitu (translated and adapted by Kimotho Karanu) (Box 33)
    - Kũng'ũ Mũirũĩ (Box 33)
    - Mwatũka wa Nyakaĩrũ (Box 33)
    - Mbũgũa wa Kahĩga (Box 33)
    - Mutitu Na Uria Maaruaga (Box 33)
    - Utonga wa Ruitho (Box 33)
    - Mwili Unaniuma [Gilbert Gicaru Githere] (Box 33)
    - Unidentified (42 folders) (Box 33, Box 34)
  - Swahili
    - Unidentified (4 folders) (Box 34)
- IV. Mũtiiri
  - Correspondence (Box 34)
  - Financial/Legal (2 folders) (Box 34)
  - Reception invitations, May 2, 1994 (Box 34)
  - Flyers/Mailouts (Box 34)
  - Information packets (Box 34)
  - Letterhead (Box 34)
  - Mailing lists (2 folders) (Box 34)
  - Draft - Vol.2 (2 folders) (Box 34)
  - Publication copy - Vol. 3, November - December 1994 (Box 35)
  - Gitahi wa Gititi (Box 35)
  - Gatua wa Mbũgwa (Box 35)
  - Art and Design (Box 35)
  - Notebook (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 35)
- V. Imprisonment
  - Detention Order (Box 35)
  - Detainees Review Tribunal (Box 35)
  - Free Ngũgĩ' Campaign (Box 35)
  - My Testament (Box 35)
  - Guidelines for Interviews on My Detainment (Box 35)
  - Petition to have Ngũgĩ' reinstated (Box 35)
- VI. Activism
  - Political Prisoners
    - Committee for the Release of Political Prisoners (Box 35)
    - Political Prisoners (5 folders) (Box 35)
  - Mwakenya
    - "Kenya Register of Resistance 1986" (Box 35)
    - Draft Minimum Programme September, 1987 (Box 35)
    - 1986 (Box 35)
    - 1987-1989 (Box 35)
    - MK News, December, 1990 (Box 35)
    - 1990 (Box 35)
    - Kenya Democracy Plank, 1991 (Box 35)
    - 1991 (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - 1992 (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - The Mwakenya Stand: On the Current Situation in Kenya, 1992 (Box 36)
    - International Newsletters, 1992 (Box 36)
    - 1993 (Box 36)
    - International Newsletters, 1993 (Box 36)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 36)
    - Meeting minutes, 1983-1996 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
    - MPATANISHI, 1982-1985 (Box 36)
    - MPATANISHI, 1992-1995 (Box 36)
    - MZALENDO, 1990-1994 (Box 36)
    - PAMBANA, 1982-1996 (Box 36)
  - Umoja/Ukenya
    - Unity Conference papers (7 folders), October 16-19 1987 (Box 36)
    - From Kimathi to Mwakenya; Resistance in Kenya Today, 1987 (Box 36)
    - Manifesto of Ukenya, 1987 (Box 37)
    - MBIU Ya Kenya Vol. 1 No. 3, April 1998 (Box 37)
    - Umoja/Ukenya (8 folders) (Box 37)
    - Cheche Kenya: Voices of Women in Struggle (Box 37)
  - Anti-Imperialist Organizations
    - Association of the People of Africa Abroad, February 1980 (Box 37)
    - GHAPSO (Ghana Peoples Solidarity Organization) (Box 37)
    - Vijana Wazalendo Wa Kenya (Kenya National Youth Movement), July 1989 (Box 37)
    - Kenya Anti-Imperialist Front (KAIF) (Box 37)
    - Kenya Democratic Party (Box 37)
    - Kenya Patriotic Front (KPF) (Box 37)
    - KEPEDEMO – Mapinduzi (Kenya People's Democratic Movement) (Box 37)
    - MEKAREMO Draft Programme of the Me Katili Revolutionary Movement (Box 37)
    - MGOGORO WA KENYA - Uganda (Box 37)
    - MOJA - GAMBIA Programme for the National Democratic Revolution (Box 37)
    - ODK Declaration (Organization for Democracy in Kenya {Sweeden}), May 24, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Proposal for a Union of African States (Box 37)
    - SWAPO (South West African Peoples' Organization), 1989 (Box 37)
    - Ubuntu Centre Draft Working Paper, 1996 (Box 37)
    - UMOJA WA WAANDISHI WA KIAFRIKA (Union of Writers of the African Peoples) (Box 37)
    - ZESWAY Manifesto (Zanzibar Economic, Social, & Welfare Association of Youth) (Box 37)
  - Anti-Imperialist Literature
    - Agrarian Revolution and Our Task, 1968 (Box 37)
    - The Republican: Magazine of the Tanzania Makerere Students Association, 1969 (Box 37)
    - The Garvey Institute Newsletter, 1971 (Box 37)
    - MAZUNGUMZO Vol.2 No.2, 1972 (Box 37)
    - Maji Maji (three volumes), 1972-1976 (Box 37)
    - AfrikaNews, 1975 (Box 37)
    - MWANGUZI No.1, April 23, 1975 (Box 37)
    - Cultural Charter for Africa, 1976 (Box 37)
    - ISIS International Bulletin, October, 1976 (Box 37)
    - Zanu Newsletter, 1976 (Box 37)
    - Oil Field Workers Trade Union, 1977-1986 (Box 37)
    - African Study Group (multi-volumes), 1978-1981 (Box 37)
    - Ugandan Voices Issue No. 3, December 1979 - April 1980 (Box 37)
    - Asian Issues, 1980 (Box 37)
    - Forward: A Call for a Democratic Uganda (multi-volumes), 1980-1984 (Box 38)
    - Ikwezi No.21, October 1982 (Box 38)
    - UDASA Newsletter (two volumes) No.3 October 1982 / No.11, June, 1990 (Box 38)
    - Inquest: United Campaigns for Justice Annual Report, 1982-1983 (Box 38)
    - Liberation Annual Report, 1983 (Box 38)
    - CARE Newsletter (Campaign Against Racial Exploitation), January - February 1983 (Box 38)
    - Direction (multi-volumes), March - August 1983 (Box 38)
    - Guyana Update No. 4, July - August 1983 (Box 38)
    - The Gambia Human Rights Review No.1, January 1984 (Box 38)
    - Tribune Africaine, March 1984 (Box 38)
    - The Nkuumaist: Organ of the Pan-African Socialist Party No. 1-2, 1984 (Box 38)
    - The New Uganda Newsletter Vol.4 No.3, May - June 1986 (Box 38)
    - Proposal for a Union of African States, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Cutlass: Bulletin of Caribbean Labor Solidarity Party (two volumes), 1987-1988 (Box 38)
    - KASAMA: Philippine Support Group Newsletter No. 27-30, 1987-1988 (Box 38)
    - The Gambia News-Letter Vol. 2, 1988 (Box 38)
    - Workers' Vanguard, April/May 1988 (Box 38)
    - New Africa News (multi-volumes), 1988-1989 (Box 38)
    - Revolutionary Banner No.10, April - May 1989 (Box 38)
    - People's Voice: Publication of the Tigray People's Liberation Front Vol.11 Nos. 2/3, May/August 1989 (Box 38)
    - Workers Revolution No. 1, August 1989 (Box 38)
    - New Burma Times Vol.2 No. 5, 1990 (Box 38)
    - The Third Republic Alternative No. 0002, July 1991 (Box 38)
    - Proletarian Revolution No. 42, 1992 (Box 38)
    - Revolutionary Worker (multi-volumes), 1992-1993 (Box 38)
    - Kenya (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Box 38)
- VII. Education
  - Makerere University (Box 38)
  - University of East Africa -Draft University Development Plan, 1964-1967 (Box 38)
  - University of Nairobi
    - 1968-1972 (Box 38)
    - 1973 (Box 38)
    - 1974 (Box 38)
    - Mila: Biannual Newsletter of Cultural Research Vol. 4 No. 1, 1974 (Box 38)
    - 1975 (Box 38)
    - January 1976 - February 1976 (Box 38)
    - March 1976 - December 1976 (Box 38)
    - January 1977 - February 1977 (Box 38)
    - March 1977 - June 1977 (Box 38)
    - July 1977 - September 1977 (Box 39)
    - October 1977 - December 1977 (Box 39)
    - 1978-1981 (Box 39)
    - University of Nairobi Syllabi, undated (Box 39)
    - Nairobi Ministry of Education Chief Inspector of Schools, 1975-1976 (Box 39)
    - Department of History Staff Seminar Papers, 1972-1977 (Box 39)
    - Institute for Development Studies Working Papers, 1974-1975 (Box 39)
    - Institute for Development Studies Discussion Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 39)
    - Institute of African Studies Seminar Papers, 1974-1976 (Box 39)
    - Institute of African Studies Seminar Papers, 1977-1979 (Box 39)
    - Institute of African Studies Discussion Papers, 1974-1977 (Box 39)
    - Institute of African Studies Working Papers, 1974-1979 (Box 39)
    - Historical Association of Kenya: The Causation of History in the Context of European Africa, 1973 (Box 39)
    - Historical Association of Kenya Annual Conference Papers, 1976 (Box 39)
    - Historical Association of Kenya Annual Conference Papers, 1977 (Box 39)
    - Historical Association of Kenya Annual Conference Papers, 1981 (Box 39)
    - Historical Association of Kenya Annual Conference Papers, 1984 (Box 39)
    - Historical Association of Kenya Annual Conference Papers, 1986 (Box 39)
    - On the Teaching of African Literature (3 folders), undated (Box 39)
    - Universal Free Education (Box 39)
    - Black Aesthetics (Box 39)
    - Proposal for Sub-department of Theatre & Media Arts, 1974 (Box 39)
    - State Violence at the University of Nairobi, Kenya, February, 1985 (Box 39)
    - The Student Chances as a Writer (Box 39)
  - Nothwestern University, 1970-1971 (Box 39)
  - Kenyatta University College, 1974-1977 (Box 39)
  - University of Botswana, Lesotho and Swaziland, 1975-1977 (Box 39)
  - Yale
    - Writers in Politics: The Relationship Between Politics & Literature in Modern Africa, 1988-1989 (Box 39)
    - Imperialism in Modern Literature - Spring, 1990 (Box 39)
    - Colonialism and African Literature - Spring, 1992 (Box 40)
    - Writing From Prison: Resistance Literature from Africa and the "Third World" - Spring, 1992 (Box 40)
  - Amherst College
    - Imperialism In Modern Literature / Colonialism and African Literature (2 folders) - Fall, 1991 (Box 39)
  - New York University (NYU)
    - Imperialism in "Third World" Literature - Fall, 1992 (Box 40)
    - Colonialism and African Literature - Spring, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Orature: The Roots of Modern African Theater - Spring, 1993 (Box 40)
    - The Post-Colonial in African Literature - Fall, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Performance and Resistance in African Prison Narratives - Fall, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Imperialism in 'Third World" Literature - Fall, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Orature: The Roots of Contemporary African Theater - Spring, 1994 (Box 40)
    - Topics in Black Literature - Spring, 1994 (Box 40)
    - Orature: The Roots of Contemporary African Theatre - Spring, 1995 (Box 40)
    - Shakespeare and the Black Diaspora - Fall, 1995 - Spring, 1996 (Box 40)
    - Postcolonialism and the African Novel - Spring, 1996 (Box 40)
    - Songs of Beauty: Performance of the African Being in Black Aesthetics - Spring, 1996 (Box 40)
    - Writers in Politics: Gender, Class and Power in African Women Writing - Spring, 1996 (Box 40)
    - Orature: The Roots of Contemporary African Theatre - Fall, 1996 (Box 40)
    - Performing History: The Aesthetics of Resistance in the Theater of Black History - Spring, 1997 (Box 40)
    - Colonialism and the Rise of African Literature - Fall, 1997 (Box 40)